Guide to the Stefan Bergman Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stefan Bergman papers
circa 1940-1972
SC0404
Bergman, Stefan, 1898-
2.5 Linear feet
Papers include professional correspondence, 1948-67, primarily with Hilda van Mises (formerly Hilda Geiringer) and Zeev Nehari; lecture notes from his teaching at M.I.T., ca. 1940; articles, reports, and reprints; annotated drafts; and other miscellaneous items.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Mathematician and pioneer in theories concerning the functions of complex variables. Born in Poland, Bergman studied in Vienna and Berlin and received his Ph.D. in 1922. He taught at the University of Berlin and at the Universities of Tomsk and Tiflis in the Soviet Union. In 1939 he moved to the United States and taught at Brown, M.I.T., and Harvard. He joined the Stanford faculty in 1952 where he taught until his retirement in 1972.
Description of the Collection
Papers include professional correspondence, 1948-67, primarily with Hilda van Mises (formerly Hilda Geiringer) and Zeev Nehari; lecture notes from his teaching at M.I.T., ca. 1940; articles, reports, and reprints; annotated drafts; and other miscellaneous items.
Access Terms
Bergman, Stefan, 1898-; Geiringer, Hilda, 1893-1973.; Nehari, Zeev, 1915-; Stanford University. Department of Mathematics. Faculty.; Mathematics.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Mises correspondence, 1948-1954 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Mises correspondence, January 1955-July 1955 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Mises correspondence, July 1955-December 1955 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Mises correspondence, January 1956-June 1959 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Nehari correspondence, May 1948-January 1951 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - General correspondence, 1948-1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, fragment (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Lecture notes, M.I.T. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Articles (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Articles with notes (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Reports (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Complex Orthogonal Functions and Conformal Mapping (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bound reprints with annotations (Box 2)
  - Bound reprints with annotations (Box 3)
  - Unbound reprints (Box 4)
  - Dissertations: Leppig, Manfred. Die Bergmansche Integralformel. Bwee Lan Tjong. Operators Generating Solutions of Certain Partial Differential Equations and Their Properties. (Box 4)
  - Integral Operators in the Theory of Linear Partial Differential Equations. (1959) annotated (Box 5)
  - Integral Operators in the Theory of Linear Partial Differential Equations. (1961) (Box 5)
  - Integral Operators in the Theory of Linear Partial Differential Equations. (1969) (Box 5)
  - The Kernel Function and Conformal Mapping. (1950) (Box 5)
  - The Kernel Function and Conformal Mapping. (1970) (Box 5)
  - Kernel Functions and Differential Equations. (1953) [written with M. Schiffer] (Box 5)
  - Sur les fonctions orthogonales de plusiers variables complexes avec les applications a la theorie des fonctions analytiques. (1947) (Box 5)
  - Journal d'Analyse Mathematique. Volume XIV [dedicated to Stefan Bergman. Signed by contributors] (Box 5)